<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware on CAN</title>
    <link>http://cansurmeli.com/tags/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hardware on CAN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://cansurmeli.com/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for iPhone Repair</title>
      <link>http://cansurmeli.com/posts/9-tips-for-iphone-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cansurmeli.com/posts/9-tips-for-iphone-repair/</guid>
      <description>For some time, I&amp;rsquo;ve been fixing my and my circle&amp;rsquo;s iPhones in terms of hardware difficulties: battery change, screen replacement, etc.
As you may know, I also open up other things but in this post, I would like to share my experiences when opening up an iPhone as in what to do and not to do.
Actually, before we get started, these are really small details that might seem funny and idiotic at first but trust me, the devil is hiding in the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Lines on iPhone Screen after Battery Replacement</title>
      <link>http://cansurmeli.com/posts/3-white-lines-on-iphone-screen-after-battery-replacement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cansurmeli.com/posts/3-white-lines-on-iphone-screen-after-battery-replacement/</guid>
      <description>I’m a DIY person. I believe in the mantra of iFixit: “repair is noble”. Even though my iPhone 6 was under warranty, I never thought of taking it to Apple to get it’s battery replaced free of charge when the battery started dying when it reached somewhere in between 30-20%. Bad battery. 😝
Maybe it was the long waiting lines of the Genius Bar or my passion for fixing stuff going on in my subconscious that lead me not to go to Apple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Adventures Opening up my iMac</title>
      <link>http://cansurmeli.com/posts/1-my-adventures-opening-up-my-imac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cansurmeli.com/posts/1-my-adventures-opening-up-my-imac/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, I performed a brain surgery on my iMac. I removed the optical disc drive, put a SSD in place and combined the SSD with the already installed HDD in order to create a fusion drive in order to achieve a much much better performance while increasing my storage.
Before I leave you out with my words, I think you should have a look at the time-lapse video of the procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>